本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：sienna   CS小明漫画家   小花豆   大红包
翻译：卫老哥  MythCreator  面条打包子  姚小事儿
翻译：七个柚子酱  feilixiaozi  木浅薰  王小麦
时间轴：大红包  贝贝  凭陵新月
校对：王小麦
后期：8T   MythCreator     总监：王小麦
真探  前情提要
她总是有各种各样的麻烦
You know, she's always been in some kind of trouble.
我原以为事情有所好转
I thought things were getting better.
跟查理分开了
Got away from Charlie.
前一阵子她还给你打过电话
She called up here for you not too long ago.
说要去当修女
She's gonna become a nun.
你昨晚干什么去了
You know, what'd you do last night?
我和女朋友们出去玩
I was out with girlfriends.
我不能在家里和好男人约会
I can't meet a nice man at home.
我只想跟你们在一起
There is nowhere else I want to be.
你可能都没意识到自己在撒谎
I wonder if you even know you're lying.
得了吧
Oh, come on!
我有一本侦探小说  写着我的两个警探无所作为
I got a whodunit where my two detectives are stalling,
还有一个特别小组想接手这案子
and I got a task force wants to take it off our hands.
所以科尔不想把案子
So Cohle didn't want to
移交给特别小组  你呢
give it to the task force. Did you?
不
No.
我知道这个地方
I heard of this place.
是个活动住房区一类的地方  她们管那里叫大农场
Kind of trailer park. They call it "The Ranch."
有个女孩遇难了  我们想知道
Something happened to a girl, and we need to know
你们有谁认识她
if any of you knew her.
对  这是朵莉
Yeah. That's Dori.
你知道她过去几周
You got any idea where she might
在哪儿呆着吗
have been staying the last few weeks?
她还去教堂  我还在指望
She'd been going to church. I was hoping maybe
也许她重新做人了
she just turned things around.
你是否迷失  孤独  耶稣会拯救你
这个地方毁了
Place is trashed.
什么东西都没有了
This ain't no kinda anything.
小马
Marty?
真探
第一季第三集
就像看不见灰烬中的足迹一样  你们也看不见祂
You were as blind to Him as your footprints in the ashes,
但祂看得见你们
but He saw you.
祂见你们蜷缩在阴暗角落
He saw you in those dark corners.
祂听得见你们
He heard you--
兄弟姐妹们  祂听得见这些念头
Oh, my brothers, He heard those thoughts.
-对  -颂扬主
- Yes! - Preach it.
-阿门  -对
- Amen! - Yes!
赞美主
Yes. Glory.
你不了解自己  而主了解你
You are stranger to yourself, and yet He knows you...
阿门  对  祂了解我们
Amen. Yes. He does, sir.
当你铁石心肠时  你会化作石头
And when your heart hardened, made you liken to the stone,
从祂身上剥离
and broke you from His body,
而祂是天上的繁星  是繁星间的和风
which is the stars and the wind between the stars,
他了解你
He knew you.
他了解你  这是永恒真理
He knew you. That is forever.
阿门  兄弟
Amen, brother!
这个世界无法看清
This world is a veil...
阿门
Amen. Yeah.
告诉他们  哈利路亚
Tell them. Hallelujah.
你现在的面目并非你自己
and the face you wear is not your own.
教区的护教士说  教堂是在4个多月前
Parish FD said the church burned down
烧毁的  没有指纹
4 months earlier, no prints,
我们发了一份基督之友教会的通缉令
put out an APB on Friends of Christ.
一周后  我们去了富兰克林
Week later, we were in Franklin,
那里的奋兴牧师
um, Revival Ministry,
有着老派的宗教作风
old-time religion.
你们可以想象魅力先生[拉斯特]是怎么想的
You can imagine what Mr. Charisma thought of that.
这不过是你感官上的限制
It is merely the limitation of your senses.
你认为这群人的
What do you think the average IQ
平均智商如何
of this group is, huh?
还有跟你一样傲慢无礼的德州人吗
Can you see Texas up there on your high horse?
你对这群人知道些什么
What do you know about these people?
就认真观察  再分析推理
Just observation and deduction.
我发现这些人都偏肥胖  贫穷
I see a propensity for obesity, poverty,
渴望童话般得美好
a yen for fairy tales,
人们把他们仅有的那点钱
folks putting what few bucks they do have
放进那个依次传递的
into little, wicker baskets
小篮子里面
being passed around.
小马  我敢确信
I think it's safe to say that nobody here
这里的人很团结
is gonna be splitting the atom, Marty.
瞧见没  你太拽了
You see that? You're fucking attitude.
没人想要独自在一间空屋
Not everybody want to sit alone in a empty room
对着谋杀手册撸管
beating off to murder manuals.
有些人喜欢团体生活  共同利益
Some folks enjoy community, the common good.
是吗  如果共同利益
Yeah? Well, if the common good
需要靠编造童话为生
has got to make up fairy tales,
那它对谁都没好处
then it's not good for anybody.
悲伤将你们禁锢于此
Your sorrows pin you to this place.
它们让你心智迷失
They divide you from what your heart knows,
世上有很多善良之心
and there are a lot of good hearts out there.
我能看到
I'm looking out there.
我能看到很多善良之心
I'm seeing a lot of good hearts out there.
看到世上很多喜悦
I see a lot of joy out there.
我说  你能想象吗
I mean, can you imagine
如果人们没有了信仰
if people didn't believe,
他们会做出什么事来
what things they'd get up to?
他们会像现在一样
Exact same thing they do now,
跑到世外来
just out in the open.
放  屁
Bull...shit.
没了信仰  这个世界将充斥着
It'd be a fucking freak show of murder
谋杀和淫逸
and debauchery, and you know it.
如果只有期待神的奖励
If the only thing keeping a person decent
才能让人走正道
is the expectation of divine reward,
那么兄弟  那种人才是垃圾
then, brother, that person is a piece of shit,
我很愿意尽我所能把他们清除到世外来
and I'd like to get as many of them out in the open as possible.
我觉得你的评论就像
I guess your judgment is infallible
臭大粪一样准确
piece-of-shitwise.
你觉得圣经是墓碑吗
Do you think that notebook is a stone tablet?
对于生命它怎么描述的
What's it say about life,
你们要聚在一起  给自己讲
you got to get together, tell yourself stories
亵渎宇宙万物法则的故事
that violate every law of the universe
只为了熬日子
just to get through the goddamn day?
-算了吧  -你就不担心吗
- No. - Don't you worry about it?
信仰怎么解决你的现实问题呢  小马
What's that say about your reality, Marty?
每次你这么说话的时候
When you get to talking like this,
感觉都很惊慌失措
you sound panicked.
你觉得那都是骗人的  是吧
You figure it's all a scam, huh,
所有人都是吗
all them folks?
他们全错了吗
They just wrong?
没错
Oh, yeah.
自从有个猴子看着太阳
Been that way since one monkey looked at the sun
对另一只猴子说
and told the other monkey,
神说  让你跟我分享你那见鬼的一切
"He said for you to give me your fucking share."
人是很脆弱的  他们宁愿
People so goddamn frail they'd rather
把钱扔进许愿井
put a coin in a wishing well
也不用来买晚餐
than buy dinner.
耶稣基督耶稣基督  你的双臂张开又闭合
Jesus Christ, Jesus Christ, Your arms open and close.
我生命的共鸣难以容纳
The echoes of my life could never contain
你的任一真理
a single truth about You.
你将翎毛移入灰烬
You move the feather in the ash.
你用它的火焰轻抚树叶
You touch the leaf with its flame.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen! - Amen.
把恐惧和自我厌恶转移到
Transference of fear and self-loathing
权威主义这个容器中
to an authoritarian vessel.
这是种宣泄
It's catharsis.
他用叙述故事来吸走他们的恐惧
He absorbs their dread with his narrative.
正因为如此  他的话能否让人信服
Because of this, he's effective
和他所勾勒的故事的确定性
in proportion to the amount of certainty
成正比
he can project.
某些语言人类学家认为
Certain linguistic anthropologists think
宗教是语言的病毒
that religion is a language virus
能改写大脑路径
that rewrites pathways in the brain,
让批判性思维变得愚钝
dulls critical thinking.
我不像你会那么多高深词汇
Well, I don't use $10 words as much as you,
但是对一个看不出生存意义的人来说
but for a guy who sees no point in existence,
你还真够发愁的
you sure fret about it an awful lot,
说这话时你还是很惊慌失措
and you still sound panicked.
至少我没有明知故犯
At least I'm not racing to a red light.
...所有自我怀疑  因为祂能得知
...every self-doubt because he knows it.
我们都遇到了我称之为"生命陷阱"的东西
See, we all got what I call a life trap,
它让你相信一切都会不同
this gene-deep certainty that things will be different,
你会搬到其它城市
that you'll move to another city
会遇到朋友  这些朋友
and meet the people that'll be the friends
会陪伴你一生
for the rest of your life,
你会陷入爱情并实现梦想
that you'll fall in love and be fulfilled.
该死的梦想成真  以及生命的完结
Fucking fulfillment, heh, and closure,
不管这两者到底是什么
whatever the fuck those two--
没有金刚钻就想揽瓷器活儿
Fucking empty jars to hold this shitstorm,
什么梦想都无法成就
and nothing is ever fulfilled
直到世界末日  而完结
until the very end, and closure--
不  不  一切都不会完结
No. No, no. Nothing is ever over.
塞里奥特牧师
Minister Theriot,
你认识这个女孩吗
do you recognize this girl?
我不确定
I don't know for sure.
您的布道太精彩了
Wonderful sermon.
感谢你能来
Well, thank you for coming.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
我得说这个
I want to say it's--
谢谢
Thank you.
我不知道名字
I don't remember the name,
我们在尤尼斯的时候经常来
came pretty regularly when we was in Eunice,
但我不是很确定
but I can't be sure.
那之后我们就在四处游荡
We get around since then.
你呢  你好
You? Oh, hello.
你说得对  我们在尤尼斯见过她
No. You're right. We saw her in Eunice.
蒂娜有可能认识她
Tina might know her.
你们在尤尼斯待了多久
How long were you in Eunice?
大约六个月
About 6 months.
奥珀卢瑟斯里一个寡妇开的租金很便宜
Widow in Opelousas leased us cheap.
那个地方着火后我们就离开了
We left when it caught fire.
知道怎么起火的吗
Any idea how that happened?
你们的人说是恶作剧升级
Your people said criminal mischief.
我猜是寡妇的其中一个儿子
If I was to lay odds, maybe one of the widow's sons
想让我们离开那里  但我们已经不计较了
wanted us off the land, but we move on.
我们既不要个说法也不寻求报复
We seek no title nor retribution.
-我去找大卫  -好的
- I'm gonna go find David. - Ok.
传道说得不错
Yeah. Great preaching.
你做这个多久了
How long you been doing this?
已经传道将近20年了
Been preaching almost 20 years.
过去八年我们组织了基督之友教会
We've had Friends of Christ for the last 8.
在这之前你在教堂待过吗
You with a church before that?
我是独立福音派教徒
Independent evangelical.
我在比利·李·塔特尔手下受教
I came up under Billy Lee Tuttle,
在他在巴顿鲁日的学校里学了几年
went to his college in Baton Rouge a couple years.
关于尤尼斯
So back in Eunice,
谁画的教堂的壁画
who painted the mural on the church wall?
我们教堂会众的孩子们画的
Children from our congregation painted it.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
这个女孩出了什么事情吗
Something happen to this girl?
你在找她吗
You looking for her?
塞里奥特先生  我们能看一下
Mr. Theriot, can we see the identification
你职员的身份证明吗
of your staff members?
你看她和谁在一起过
You ever see her with anybody?
有一天她好像和某个人在一起
Wasn't she with someone the one day?
你记得吗  高个男人
You remember? The tall man.
记得  但我不知道
Yeah, but I don't know
她是不是和他"在一起"那样的在一起
if she was "with him" with him.
你能向我描述一下他吗
Well, can you describe him?
我只是看见他们在说话
I just saw them talking.
我没有靠近或是怎么样
I didn't get close or anything.
他身体前倾和她说话
He was hunched forward talking to her,
是张陌生面孔  我觉得
kind of a strange face, I think,
下巴周围的皮肤很有光泽
skin shiny around his jaw.
什么样的  像是烧伤那样的吗
Ah, what, like burned?
所以他们俩一起离开的吗
So did she leave with him?
是的  应该是这样
Yeah, maybe like that.
89年10月因为妨害风化罪被逮捕
Arrested 10/89 on a 314,
去年一次帮派纠纷后一直在关禁闭
spent last year in solitary after a gang altercation.
打出来收好  谢谢
Print and hold. Thank you.
收到
Copy that.
所有事都查清楚了吗
Everything check out?
重要的都知道了
For the most part.
伯特  你在安哥拉待了两年
Burt, you spent two years in Angola--
猥亵行为  公开暴露
indecency, public exposure,
在学校外撸管
whacking off outside a school.
他们给我的药有问题  我不知道
They gave me bad medicine. I didn't know.
我付过钱的  我付过钱的
I paid for that. I paid for that.
你知道他在12月25号
Can you account for his whereabouts
到1月3号之间的行踪吗
December 25 through January 3?
圣诞节到元旦
Yeah. Christmas to New Year's,
我们在新罗兹
we was in New Roads.
可以找到很多人
Shouldn't be a problem to find people
来担保伯特的行踪
who'll vouch for Burt's whereabouts.
当时到会者很多
We had a good turnout there.
很多到会者在
Good turnout in--
警探  你觉得是怎么回事
Detective, what is it you think happened?
有人杀了这个女孩  用她的尸体大做文章
Someone killed this girl, made a big show of it...
在你们的一间旧教堂上
left a painting of the crime scene
留下了一幅犯罪现场的画
on one of your old churches.
"对信吾之人
"I am the resurrection and the light
吾即复活和光明"
for those who believe in me."
她被强奸了吗  警探
Was she raped, detective?
为什么这么问
Why would you ask that?
如果你单独和伯特谈谈
If you speak to Burt alone,
我相信你会明白
I believe you'll be adequately convinced
他是无辜的  警探
of his innocence, detective.
好吧  就这么办
OK. Let's do that.
伯特  跟警探走一趟
Burt, go with the detective.
期待光明就在黑暗尽头
The ontological fallacy of expecting
这一存在论的谬论
a light at the end of the tunnel,
这就是传道士的伎俩
well, that's what the preacher sells,
跟精神病医生的手法一样
same as a shrink.
传道士  他激发起
See, the preacher, he encourages
你的幻想力
your capacity for illusion.
然后他跟你说这他妈的是种美德
Then he tells you it's a fucking virtue.
能这么做的都不简单
Always a buck to be had doing that,
听起来又是如此理所当然  不是吗
and it's such a desperate sense of entitlement, isn't it?
"毫无疑问  这一切都是为了我"
"Surely, this is all for me".
"我"
"Me".
"我  我  我  我  我"
"Me, me, me. I, I."
"我可真他妈的重要"
"I'm so fucking important."
"我可真他妈的重要  对吗"
"I'm so fucking important, then, right?"
-去你妈的  -我们出去一下
- Fuck you. - Excuse us for a second.
我不知道
I didn't know.
别紧张  我不会伤害你的
Easy. I am not gonna hurt you.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
怜悯是种美德  警探
Compassion is ethics, Detective.
的确如此
Yes. It is.
我调查了他们所有人
I ran checks on all of them.
除了伯特  所有人都没有不良记录
Everyone has got a clean record except for Burt.
我觉得这有点像是白痴做的事
I could see this being some kind of retard job--
有人指使  感到羞愧
pays for it, gets ashamed,
反应过度
overreacts,
试图挽回  如此种种  你觉得呢
tries to redeem the act, like, you know?
推理的不错  小马
That's not bad, Marty...
是啊
Well, yeah.
在没有你的帮助之下我自己想出来的
I got all the way there without your help.
不过凶手不是他
But it's not him.
他因为裸下体在农场里度过了一段艰难的日子
He did a deuce at the farm for dick wagging.
应该待在精神病院的
Should've been in a mental ward to begin with.
后来呢
Give me the second half.
在安哥拉
Angola.
几个布拉德族人趁洗澡时抓住了他
Some Bloods caught him in the shower,
用剃刀割了他的蛋蛋
took his balls off with a razor.
他们对此还不以为然
They were sloppy about it.
天呐
Oh, Jesus.
但是
Still--
我碰了他下
I braced him.
他就拉裤子上了  字面意思
He shit himself, literally.
我们可以派些警察守在这儿
We can put some troopers on this place,
监视他们
have them surveil it,
但是我觉得我们该查下一条线索了
but I think we should move on,
那个高个子男人
the tall man.
那可能只是胡说八道的
Well, that could be bullshit.
一个人说了
One threw it out,
其他人跟着一起这么说
and the other one picked up on it.
不  伯特知道
No. Burt knew.
他也看见那个高个子男人了
He saw the tall man, too.
这个人
This,
那玛丽·方特诺特案
that Marie Fontenot thing,
兰不会是他的第一个受害者
there's no way Lange was his first,
绝不可能
no fucking way.
罗西  能帮他们推下车吗
Rosie, can you help them get out, please.
我们还没查出任何匹配特征
We haven't matched any signatures.
在联邦数据库里有个人用过王冠
One guy in the fed database used crowns,
有人用过鹿角
another a set of antlers--
是个在密歇根的无期徒刑犯
Michigan lifer.
他说这些特征不符合
Then he called the signature wrong.
我们不知道这和玛丽·方特诺特之间
We don't know that there's any connection
有什么联系
to Marie Fontenot.
是啊  不过这种布阵  这种符号
Yeah, but the lattices, the symbology--
蕴含着某种文化  小马
some kind of culture to it, Marty.
他想要我们找到这具尸体
I mean, he wanted us to find this one,
就像他在炫耀
like he was showing off.
那片甘蔗地就是我们的舞台
That cane field is our stage.
那就快想想招儿
Make a suggestion, then.
再没线索  这案子就会移交给特别小组了
We start at zero, they're gonna hand it to the task force.
有人漏掉了些什么
Well, somebody missed something.
我们得回去  检查所有文件
We need to go back, check all files.
过去五年在本州发现的所有尸体
Any DBs in state the last 5 years,
我们从那儿开始
we start there.
我们没那时间
We don't have the hours.
该死的  伙计
Shit, man. Look.
我发现你有点缺乏远见
I've noticed you have a tendency toward myopia,
目光短浅  搞砸调查
tunnel vision, blows investigations.
扭曲事实  曲解证据
Vision skews, twists evidence.
你太沉迷了
You're obsessive.
你也沉迷  只不过不是沉迷工作
You're obsessive, too, just not about the job.
我才没有呢  哥们
Not, me, brother.
我把事情分得很开  一样重要
I keep things even, separate,
就好像我可以把这瓶酒干了
like the way I can have this one beer
而不会洒出来
without needing 20.
不懂内疚的人往往过得挺好
People incapable of guilt usually do have a good time.
只是不想对自己太苛刻
Try not to be too hard on myself.
真了不起啊
Well, that's real big of you.
你知道咱俩之间真正的区别是什么吗
You know the real difference between you and me?
知道  否认
Yeah. Denial.
区别在于我知道想法和现实
The difference is that I know the difference
两者之间的区别
between an idea and a fact.
你不愿承认疑惑
You are incapable of admitting doubt.
对我来说就是否认
Now, that sounds like denial to me.
我表示怀疑
I doubt that.
我们要对脸上有疤的
We'll put out an APB
高个男子发通缉令
on any tall man with facial scarring...
行
Ok.
给医院发电报寻找符合特征的病人
Telex the hospitals for patients that fit.
好
Good.
所以科尔想瞒着特别小组
So Cohle was trying to keep it from the task force.
回想一下  你有没有想过
Looking back, you ever think maybe
他可能是想把事情
he tried to push things
往他希望的方向推动呢
where he wanted them to go?
没有  我们一直被案子牵着走
No. We went where the case led us.
但你还是接受了
But you took it up, though,
他的连环杀手理论
his serial theory.
虽然他傲慢自大
Well, as arrogant as he could be,
但他是对的
he was right.
所以我们才能抓住凶手
I mean, that's how we got our man.
但我喜欢这样  知道吗
But I like it this way, you know?
很稳定
It's steady.
胡说八道
Bullshit, really.
我接受过婚姻咨询
Look. I did all the counseling and stuff.
就应该是这个样子
This is just the way things are.
不  事情是会变的
No. Things don't stay the same.
留下想要的  把其他的抛在身后
Pick up what you keep, and you leave the rest behind.
人会变好
People get better.
没错  我觉得我确实变好了
Well, that's the thing. I think I am better.
你真那么觉得吗
You really think so?
没错  相信我吧
Uh, trust me.
也许你觉得自己喜欢这种方式
Maybe you just think you prefer it this way
只是因为这是你习惯的方式
because it's what you're used to.
你适应了自己的生活
Your life accommodates you.
你没必要害怕失去
You don't have to be afraid of loss.
我跟你说的那些人就是这样
Those are the guys I was telling you about.
他们养条狗  钓钓鱼  诸如此类
They get a dog, fish, what have you.
你开始那样的生活  就会一直那样生活下去
You start with that. You live with it.
我想你可以给我介绍个护士
Hell, I suppose you could set me up with a nurse,
给我点好药
get me some of the good drugs.
新的开始
New start.
爸爸
Daddy. Daddy.
你们好  孩子们
Hey, kids.
你好  亲爱的
Hey, honey.
你好吗  小马
How you doing, Marty?
这什么情况  拉斯特
What's going on, Rust?
他把割草机送回来了
Brought the mower back.
给我的院子割草了
Mow my yard?
是啊  我看需要修剪一下
Yeah. I saw it needed mowing,
就当是还人情  谢谢你们借我割草机
returned the favor, borrowing.
我们要做炖虾
We got etouffee,
想让拉斯特留下来吃晚饭
trying to get Rust to stay for dinner.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
留下来吃晚饭  拉斯特
Stay for dinner, Rust.
不了  我想我该走了
Nah. I think I got to get.
玛姬  谢谢你的茶
Maggie, thank you for the tea.
真遗憾
Sorry to hear that.
周一见
See you Monday.
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
怎么了
What?
你以为你在干什么  你这家伙
What the hell do you think you're doing, man,
趁我不在上我家
at my house when I'm not here?
来归还割草机
Returning the mower.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
给我割草
You mow my lawn? Hmm?
你以为你不在的时候
Just what'd you think I'd be doing over here
我会在这里做什么  小马
when you're not around, Marty?
你和我  咱俩之间有什么问题吗
What's our problem, you and me?
没问题
No problem.
我只不过不想你打理
I just don't ever want you
我的草坪  好吗
mowing my lawn, all right?
我喜欢自己动手
I like mowing my lawn.
那是你支持的队伍吗  爸爸
That is your team, Daddy?
是的  宝贝儿  我希望他们能赢
Yeah, baby. That-- I want them to win.
奥德丽  你妈妈和我
Uh, hey, Audrey, your mom and I
想和你谈谈
want to talk to you a minute about
你在学校画的画  好吗
those drawings you did in school, yeah?
梅斯  回房间去
Mace, run to your room.
为什么
Why?
因为我这么说额  回
Because I said so. Run to y--
走  快走
Go. Go on.
走
Go.
走  跑起来
Go. Run.
听着
Look.
你不用紧张  好吗  宝贝
You don't have to get upset, honey, OK?
我们只是想和你谈谈
We just want to talk to you.
你以前在哪儿看到那些的
Where'd you see that before, hmm?
你为什么画那些东西
Why'd you draw that?
因为其他女孩喜欢
Because other girls liked it
而且觉得很有趣
and they thought it was funny.
就是这样
That's all.
但是你为什么会想画那些东西呢
Yeah, but where'd you get that idea, hmm?
女孩们说我不敢那么做
The girls dared me to do it.
上帝啊
Oh, God.
那会让人生气的  奥德丽
That upsets people, Audrey.
太丑了
It's ugly.
那让美好的事物变得
It makes something that should be nice
丑陋
ugly.
对不起
I'm sorry. Oh...
没事的  没事的
Shh. That's OK. It's OK.
没事的  宝贝
It's OK, sweetie.
我不是说我有资格这么说
Well, I'm not saying that I got any room to talk,
不过你知道做一名父亲意味着什么吗
but do you know what it means to be a father?
那意味着你要对家人负责
It means you are accountable for other people.
你要为他们的生命负责
You are responsible for their lives.
从某个角度来讲
Now, past a certain point,
这些责任里有一些毫无意义的事
there's a futility in responsibility.
你就这么点担心吗
That's the extent of your concern?
不
Well, no.
我只是不觉得一直看下去能有什么意义
I just don't know what looking at it any more is gonna do.
我担心的是她
It's her. I'm concerned.
她只是想得到关注
Well, she's just trying to get attention,
其他女孩
and the other girls--
上帝  她们也太早熟了吧
Jesus, how do they even know about that stuff yet?
女孩子比男孩子更早懂这些事
Girls always know before boys.
为什么
Why is that?
因为必须这样
Because they have to.
听着  她很不合群
Listen to me. She's withdrawn.
她打听过你的事  想知道
She asks about you, and she wants to know
为什么你现在工作这么忙
why you're working so much now.
我很快就没这么忙了
Well, I should be working less.
特别小组会接手那个案子
Task force is gonna take that case,
我也会多待在家里
and I'll be around more.
上周的事了吧
Last week?
我很抱歉  我应该推掉的
I'm sorry about that. I should've begged off.
我们那天晚上过得不错
We were having a good night.
别打断我  说出来
Don't stop me. Talk.
我快撑不住了  小马
I'm close, Marty.
你听到了吗  我快撑不住了
Do you hear me? I'm close.
他们会把案子从我们手里接走的
Um, they're gonna pull that case from us,
我会多陪陪你们的  我们可以做很多事
and I'll be around more, and we'll do things.
我们之间为什么有这么多隔阂  小马
Why is there all this space between us, Marty?
我不懂你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
你懂的
You do know what I mean,
但你就是不说  问题就在于此
and you won't say, and that's it.
那就是我说的
That's what I'm talking about.
去年  你表现得像个阴沉的小孩
This last year, you've been a sulky teenager.
你知道的
You know it.
我想当你的朋友  小马
I'm trying to be your friend, Marty.
我只是不善于  表达
I'm just not good at... you know... expressing.
我们都会改变的  不是吗
We change, don't we,
虽然有时不会变太久
and sometimes not for long.
而我认为人根本不会变
And here I'm thinking people don't really change at all,
内心深处永远是同一个人
not who they are at heart.
我一直试着回忆过去
I try to remember things
因为我觉得自己必须这么做
because I feel like I should,
就好像这是我的工作
like it's my job or something,
回忆过去的时光
you know, early days,
而我已经厌倦了回忆过去
and I'm tired of trying to remember.
部分原因是...
Part of this--
我并不是在否认这全是我的错
and I'm not talking about the part that's all my fault--
但部分原因在于  这就是生活
but part of it, it's just life.
我们以前经常整个周末都待在房间里
We used to spend weekends without leaving my room.
-我指的不是这个  -记得吗
- That's not what I mean. - Remember that?
我们当然不再像十九岁时那样夜夜欢歌
Of course we don't screw like we're 19.
天  你的期望真低
God, you want low expectations.
你根本不思进取
You put a ceiling on your life,
任何事都是  因为你不想改变
on everything, because you won't change.
我刚认识你时  你比现在聪明多了
You were so much smarter when I met you, you know?
我很抱歉  玛姬
I'm sorry, Maggie.
所有的一切我都很抱歉
I'm sorry for everything--
因为没有陪在你们身边
for not being here,
认为一切都理所应当
for taking all this for granted.
你一直都在干什么  小马
What have you been doing, Marty?
我...
I--
工作  家庭  办案
work, home, cases.
只是...
Just--
我的感觉就像
I get to feeling like--
我想着四十岁时的样子
Look. I can see 40...
[源自卡通《BB鸟和大野狼》]
感觉自己就像动画片中的大野狼
and it's like I'm that coyote in the cartoons,
跑过了悬崖
like I'm running off a cliff,
如果我不往下看继续跑的话
and if I don't look down and keep running,
可能就没事  但如果
I might be fine, but, um...
看来我把一切都搞砸了
I think I'm all fucked up.
确实如此
You are.
没错  你搞砸了
Yes. You are.
小马
Marty?
话说回来  我们抓了几个医院的病人
Anyway, well, we pulled a few hospital patients--
高个子  脸上有疤  性侵犯者
tall, scarred, sex offenders.
有个孩子是非法侵入的惯犯
One kid did B&Es.
每一次犯事都要顺点东西走才行
He had to tug one out before he could leave a scene.
当时在审讯室可待了不少时间
Yeah. A lot of room work then.
你们谁比较擅长审讯
Which one of you guys is the box man?
是你  对吧
You, yeah?
我以前审讯的本事也不差
I used to be pretty good in there myself,
但还是比不上拉斯特
not as good as Rust.
我明白  孩子
I know, son.
我能理解你
I can read this off you.
你的本质并不坏  那不是真正的你
You're not bad. It's not you.
都是因为某个东西
There's a weight,
它在你灵魂深处诱惑着你
and it got its fishhooks in your heart and your soul.
你的所作所为并不是你的错
Now, what you did is not your fault.
不是
It's not.
你的人生是被那东西毁掉的
You was drug to the bottom by that same weight,
它让你无法好好工作
the same weight that won't let you get along in a job,
它让你无法正常上学
and same weight that wouldn't let you get along at school...
它让你无法获得母爱
same weight that wouldn't let you have a mom.
我都了解  克里斯
I know these things, Chris.
我太软弱  我有病
I'm weak. I'm sick.
我闯进别人家里
I get into the houses,
不翻遍所有抽屉就没法离开
and I can't leave until I go all over the drawers.
听我说  孩子
Listen to me, son.
你有一条出路
You got one way out,
就是籍着上帝的恩典
and it's through the grace of God.
是主将你创造成这个样子
You're only how the Lord made you.
你并无瑕疵
You are not flawed.
我们  你  我  所有人
We, you, me, people,
都没法选择自己的感受
we don't choose our feelings.
这个世界蒙受圣恩
There's grace in this world,
所有人都能得到宽恕
and there's forgiveness for all,
但首先你得请求原谅
but you have to ask for it.
我请求  我请求  我希望得到宽恕
I do. I do. I want that.
我希望被宽恕  我在请求  真心请求
I want it. I want that. I'm asking. I'm asking.
告诉我  快告诉我
Tell me. Tell me.
求你告诉我应该说什么
Please just tell me what to say.
我坦白  什么都坦白
I want to confess. I want to confess.
抱歉久等了
Sorry about that.
你的审讯记录  伙计  真是非同凡响
Your assist record, man, that's something else.
有什么秘诀吗
Any pointers?
我从来没觉得有多难
Oh, I never really found it that hard.
只需要看着他们  设身处地去想
You just look at somebody and think like they think,
消极能力
negative capability.
我觉得这是种技能
I mean, I guess it's a skill.
大多数时候  连这个都不用
Most times, you don't even need that.
只要看着他们的眼睛
You just look them in the eyes.
整个故事都会浮现出来
The whole story is right there.
所有人的饥渴与目的都无法掩饰
Everybody wears their hunger and their haunt, you know?
只需要坦诚接受这一切
You just got to be honest about what can go on up here,
这是个密室
a locked room....
不过再说一次  我很不会玩牌
but then again, I'm terrible at cards.
在我们拷问非法侵入和焚烧被害者的人渣的同时
Yeah. So while we were grilling B&E jerkoffs and burn victims,
我决定好好利用失眠症
I decided to put insomnia to good use.
嫌疑车辆
可能原因
人类
People.
我亲眼见过数千条生命的完结
I've seen the finale of thousands of lives, man
年轻人  老人
young, old.
每个人都毫不质疑自己的真实性
Each one is so sure of their realness,
认为自己的感觉经验使其成为独一无二的个体
that their sensory experience constituted a unique individual
有目标  有意义
with purpose, meaning...
从不认为自己只是生物界的玩偶
so certain that they were more than a biological puppet.
但是真相终会大白  大家都会发现
Well, the truth wills out, and everybody sees
一旦提线被割断  所有人都会倒下
once the strings are cut, all fall down.
玛姬说他很害羞
Maggie says he's shy.
我不觉得
I wouldn't say that.
表达想法的时候可不害羞
Definitely not shy about speaking his mind.
我不是这个意思
Well, that's not what I mean.
我是说他的性格  他很不安
His personality. He's edgy.
是啊  很紧张  或者说很内向
Yeah, intense, more like, introverted.
我不想再遇到醉鬼了
I don't want another drunk.
上次带我见的那个警察
The last cop you showed me--
等等  史蒂夫当时很不好过
No. Wait. Steve was going through a tough time.
他吐在我膝盖上了
He threw up in my lap.
别担心这个
Don't worry about that.
能让他靠近你的膝盖就不错了
Getting him near you lap is gonna be the challenge.
说曹操曹操到
Oh, hey, speak of the devil.
-你好  拉斯特  -马丁
- Hey, Rust. - Martin.
-嘿  玛姬  -你好  拉斯特
- Hey, Maggie. - Hi, Rust.
珍妮弗  这是拉斯丁
Jennifer. Rustin.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
你走路来的吗
Well, you walk over here?
好吧
Well...OK.
我还以为他不能更奇怪了
Just when I thought he couldn't get any stranger.
你认真的吗
Are you serious?
他尝颜色的味道
He tastes colors.
所以同感是什么
So what is synesesia?
是通感
Synesthesia.
是联合接收器和触发器的在某些方面的错位
It's a misalignment of synaptic receptors and triggers
例如碱质  色彩  或特定金属
alkalis, colors, certain metallics.
是超敏性的一种
It's a type of hyper sensitivity.
某一感官能刺激另外一种
One sense triggers another sense.
有时候我看到一种颜色
Sometimes I'll see a color,
嘴里会尝到一种味道
and it'll put a taste in my mouth.
触感  纹理或气味都能在我头脑中留下记号
A touch, a texture, a scent may put a note in my head.
我从来没听说过
I've heard that.
可能是抑制素的副作用
It can be a side effect of a statin.
这不是副作用
It's not a side effect.
如果某种东西感觉很好
So when something feels good,
是不是意味着加倍的好
does that mean it feels twice as good,
两种不同的方式
like from two different ways?
会的  是啊
It could. Yeah.
服务员会送来的  亲爱的
The waitress will bring them, babe.
干嘛要等呢  我马上回来
Why wait? I'll be right back.
续满  两杯朗姆
Refill and two rums.
能再来杯啤酒吗
Hi. Can I have another beer?
谢谢
Thank you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你看着像什么
What's it look like?
我在约会  你不也是吗
I'm on a date. Aren't you?
所以你要跟那个人回家吗
So are you gonna go home with this guy?
这真的不关你事
It's really none of your business.
你上了你老婆吧
Do you fuck your wife?
你想让我怎么样
What do you want me to do?
听着  你是想靠这样让我离婚吗
Look. Is this your way of trying to talk divorce?
上帝啊  小马  我不想跟你结婚
My God, Marty, I don't want to marry you.
这是我的重点
That's my whole point.
顺其自然吧
It's just run its course.
别这样  过来  一起喝一杯
No, it hasn't. Come here. Have a shot with me.
我可不光是来喝酒的
I didn't just come here to drink, you know.
我先去把这个放下
Let me just set this down.
会很有意思的
It'll be fun.
是啊
Yeah.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Oh, nothing.
我还以为看到个该待在教区的家伙
Thought I saw a guy who supposed to be in parish.
阿拉斯加怎么样
So what's Alaska like?
很美
It's beautiful.
不是巴黎那种美  但很干净
It's not Paris, but it's clean,
也很清澈
and it's clear.
你去过巴黎
You've been to Paris?
待过一个月
For a month.
你在巴黎干了什么
What'd you do in Paris?
基本就只是在圣母院前面喝得醉醺醺的
Mainly just got drunk in front of Notre Dame.
每一具平静的肉体都很清楚
Each stilled body so certain
它不仅仅是冲动的集合
that they were more than the sum of their urges,
所有这些无用的旋转  疲惫的心灵
all the useless spinning, tired mind,
欲望和无知的碰撞
collision of desire and ignorance.
你问到了审讯
You asked about the interrogations.
想知道真相吗
You want to know the truth?
我从未在一间房里待过十分钟以上
I never been in a room more than 10 minutes
还不知道是不是那家伙干的
and didn't know whether the guy did it or not.
你们又是花了多久才知道的
How long does it take you?
拉斯特花了大把业余时间来研究尸体
Rust spent a lot of off duty running DBs,
有几星期吧  上辈子肯定是只猎犬
weeks of it, coon hound in another life.
也有攻击黑人之意
攻击黑人
Coon hound?
我指的是单纯的猎犬
I meant raccoon hound.
现在的人都他妈容易大惊小怪的
Everybody is a fucking drama queen nowadays.
老天  听着
Jesus. Look.
如果照他的理论做  如果他的工作
If working his theories, if his job
就是让他随心所欲  那也没关系
was his idea of himself, fine.
可我们剩下这些人是有家庭的
I mean, the rest of us had families,
有亲友  还有其他美好的事物
people in our lives, good things.
人们给你规定
People give you rules.
规定就是用来描述事物的轮廓
Rules describe the shape of things.
出来
Come on!
我操
Fuck you!
操  小马  快滚
Fuck, Marty, get out of here.
"操  小马"  这就是你想对我说的
"Fuck, Marty." Is that all you got for me?
够了  回家去  我不想继续这样了
Stop it. Go home. I don't want this anymore.
你屋里藏着奸夫吗
You got that little shitbird in here?
滚  不然我报警了
Go away. I'll call the cops.
我倒要看看报警有没有用
Well, let's see how that works out for you.
-我认识别的警察  -好吧
- I know other cops. - OK.
出去  小马  出去
Get out. Marty, get out.
她说她是单身的
But she said she was single.
小马  天哪  住手  快住手
Marty, God! Stop! Stop it!
她给你吹箫了吗
Did she suck your dick, huh?
住手
Stop it!
她给你吹箫了吗
She suck your fucking dick?
住手  滚出去  下来
Stop it! Get out! Get off.
下来
Get off!
要试试这个吗
Yeah. You try it?
你自己说  不然我就让
Oh, you tell me, or I'll have
监狱第九区的女人把你的脸当避孕套用
some Ninth Ward prison queen wearing your face for a condom.
她给你吹箫了吗
Did she suck your dick?
就一点点
Just for a little bit.
下来
Get off.
求你住手
Please stop it.
抱歉揍了你的脸  伙计
Sorry I got in your face, guy.
我以前不这样
I wouldn't have really done something like that.
我不是神经病
I'm not a psycho.
所以我总说拉斯特需要一个家
That's why I always said I think Rust needed a family.
可以划清界限  界限是个好东西
It's boundaries. Boundaries are good.
我是科尔
This is Cohle.
拉斯特  你在家
Rust, you're home.
-是我  -怎么了
- It's me. - Yeah. What's wrong?
对不起
I'm sorry.
史蒂夫·杰瑞西说他遇到点事
Steve Geraci said he caught something.
他需要帮助
He needed help.
我差点给局里打电话了  可有什么用
I almost called the station, but what's the point?
你知道他们都会说谎
You know they lie.
我只能给你添麻烦了
I got to put you on the spot.
你知道这是真的吗
You know if it's true?
我什么都没听说
I didn't hear anything,
不过就算有事我也不会知道
but then again, I wouldn't.
杰瑞西不会告诉我的
I mean, Geraci wouldn't pull me.
他讨厌我
He hates me.
你把珍送回家了
You drop Jen at home?
是  我把她送到了门口
Yeah. I walked her to the door.
你没进去吗
You didn't go in?
没必要非得一见钟情
You don't have to fall in love at first sight, you know.
我知道  她人很好  很漂亮
Yeah. I know. Look. She's nice, pretty.
那里能让你感到温暖  拉斯特
There's comfort there, Rust.
你们俩会相处得很好
I think you guys would be good together
只要你愿意一试
if you gave it a chance.
你们从来不去尝试
You guys don't give things chances.
我真是搞不懂
I don't know why that is.
那是因为我们清楚自己想要什么
That's because we know what we want
而且不介意孑然一身
and we don't mind being alone.
睡觉去吧  玛姬
Go to bed, Maggie.
小马很快就会回家了  保重
Marty'll be home. Take care.
老天爷  连续三天
Holy shit, 3 days in a row.
这是最新纪录吗
Is that a new personal record?
滚一边去
Fuck off.
别逼我到你家屋顶上拉屎
I will take my first shit through your sunroof.
我好像找到了一条线索
Hey, hey, I found one, I think,
更早之前的一个女孩  过来
another girl from earlier. Come here.
三年前  阿比维尔发生了洪灾
3 years ago, a flood in Abbeville,
他们从河里捞出了这个女孩
they pulled this girl out of the river.
等一下
Hold it.
这上面说她的死是意外
It says here that her death was accidental--
溺水  肺部进水
drowned, water in the lungs.
怎么会是被他害死的
How's that him?
法医说是洪水中的树枝和碎石
Coroner says the branches and debris from the flood
造成了这些伤痕
caused these injuries, all right?
这能解释肋骨和胳膊上的伤痕
I understand the ribs and the arms,
但舌骨上的呢
but the hyoid?
-还是不  -解释不了
- Still, that's not.. - No fucking way.
看这  腹部的撕裂伤
Look at this, lacerations to the abdomen,
还检测出她服用了冰毒和迷幻剂
plus she was positive for meth and LSD.
他们说她磕了药  失足落水
They said she was high, fell in.
看她的后背
Look at the posterior.
-老天爷  -没错
- Holy shit. - Yeah.
她叫莉安·奥利弗
I.D.ed as Rianne Olivier--
22岁  住在人口三百人的
22, lives in Pelican Island,
鹈鹕岛
population 300.
祖父仍在世  住在一个码头上
Grandpa is still there, got a phone at the dock.
我可没法让人相信这东西
I don't know if I can sell this shit.
我们就顺着这个线索查两天
Two days, we dig in this direction.
如果这是他干的  那这就是原始手法
If this is his, it's some kind of archetype.
维尔普拉特发现了一具机械师的尸体
DB, Ville Platt, machinist.
你们去查
You're up.
我们这案子有线索了  头儿
Hey, we caught a break in the case, boss.
我以为你们已经不管那个案子了
I thought you were handing that off.
什么线索
What break?
和被害者有关系的一个人  可能知道凶手身份
KA of the victim. Might've known the killer, boss.
可能看到过凶手  我们要去查查
Might've seen him. We follow up.
我们还有几天时间
We still got a few days.
就两天  然后将它交给特别小组
Two days, and it goes to task force.
你们俩再查机械师的案子
You two catch again.
我们应该把连环杀手的想法跟他说说
We'll try that serial theory out on him,
光凭不喜欢你这一点他就会把你撤掉
he will pull you just for spite.
鹈鹕岛离这里两小时车程
Pelican Island is two hours away.
我们走吧
Here we go.
将你的手放到他的手上
Put your hand in his hand.
一个好的教堂会教你
The good church teaches that
基督教堂则不会教你
the Christian church does not teach that,
天主教堂也不会...
the Catholic church does not--
假设一个男人可以同时爱上两个女人
Think a man can love two women at once,
互相深爱的那种
I mean, be in love with them?
我觉得那个男人根本就不会爱
I don't think that man can love,
至少不是他自以为的那种方式
at least not the way that he means.
现实生活中总有缺陷
Inadequacies of reality always set in.
这些管道把这片土地分割得像拼图一样
This pipeline is carving up this coast like a jigsaw.
三十年后这地方就会被水淹了
Place is gonna be underwater in 30 years.
你觉得...
Do you think--
你有没有怀疑过自己是个坏人
Do you wonder ever if you're a bad man?
没有  我从不怀疑  小马
No. I don't wonder, Marty.
世界需要坏人
World needs bad men.
靠我们才能把其他坏人拒之门外
We keep the other bad men from the door.
那就是他
That's him.
你最后见到孙女是什么时候
When's the last time you saw your granddaughter?
她四年前离家出走了  就像她妈妈一样
She left 4 years ago, like her ma.
她有那样的下场理所应当
Wasn't surprised they found her like that.
每个人都认为他们会违背本性成为另一种人
Yeah. Everybody think they gonna be something they not.
每个人  都打着这种算盘
Everybody, they got this big plan.
她有男朋友吗  某个男人
She had a boyfriend you know about, a man?
她和勒杜家的一个好上了
Eh, she took up with that Ledoux fella --
比她大  家境不好
older boy, shit family --
跟他私奔了
run off with him.
还从没人问过我关于他的事
I ain't never had nobody ask me about him before.
他只说她死于洪水
He just tell me she died in the flood.
勒杜的家人还住在附近吗
That Ledoux family, they still live around here?
或许还有几个表亲吧
Oh, maybe a cousin or two.
一年比一年少了
Been shrinking every year.
大多都因为安德鲁飓风搬走了
Hurricane Andrew wiped most of the folks out around here.
知道勒杜叫什么吗
So you got a full name on that Ledoux boy?
雷吉
Reggie.
雷吉·勒杜
Reggie Ledoux.
父亲叫巴特·勒杜
Father is Bart Ledoux --
醉鬼渔夫
works offshore, drunkard.
听说他死了
I heard he died. Heh.
莉安在哪里上的学
So where'd Rianne go to school?
光明之路  在它关门之前
Light of Way when it was open.
除了坐车去阿布维尔的孩子都去那上学
Kids either went there or they were bussed to Abbeville.
州里规定两小时车程外才能做校车
State said a kid got to be bussed two hours away to school.
我倒不是很在意他们
I ain't too big on them god botherers.
跟州里比起来政府
Between them and the government --
她的父母呢  她还有其他亲戚吗
How about her parents, other relatives?
父亲是个水手兼商人
Father is a merchant seaman.
母亲去了加利福尼亚  就我所知
Mother is in California, last I heard.
你有没有她的东西
Do you have anything of hers -- possessions,
能让我们了解一下
anything that'd give us
她是个什么样的人
an idea what she might have been like?
你们调查这些干什么
What you boys looking all this up for?
她不是在洪水里淹死的吗
I was told she drowned in the flood.
我也不傻的
Now, I ain't no idiot.
难道她不是被淹死的
You telling me she ain't done drowned?
我们还不确定  先生
We don't know that, sir.
我们只是在找可能认识她的一个男人
We're just looking for a man who might have known her.
哪个
Who?
我们也想知道
That's what we're trying to figure out.
他有一盒她的东西
He ended up having a little box of her stuff,
10年级的同学录
had her last yearbook, tenth grade,
老人的话完全听不出什么
not a hint of feeling from the old man,
简直是盲人摸象
kind of got blinders,
可他为什么留着那盒东西
but why'd he keep the box, huh?
他自己知道吗
Did he ask himself?
不管怎样  我想那是一种忘记的方式
Anyway, I guess, that's one way to do it --
一门心思放在蟹笼上
keep your eyes on the crab traps.
让我想起了拉斯特
Kind of reminded me of Rust a little bit.
学校不大
This school is small,
光明之路  10年级
1到12年级都有
grades one through 12.
莉安·奥利弗  在这  10年级
Rianne Olivier. Here she is, tenth grade.
非营利教会  由塔特尔教会思源计划赞助
学校隶属塔特尔基金会
This school was part of Tuttle's foundation.
下午好
Good afternoon.
Afternoon.
这里92年就关闭了对吧
This place shut down '92, right?
我听说好像是这么回事
Yeah, the way I heard it.
你听说过什么
What'd you hear?
都是安德鲁飓风
Oh, Andrew blew it out.
可能他们觉得打扫这是白费劲吧
Guess they didn't think it was worth cleaning up.
你在这工作吗
Do you work here, then?
不  长官  教区雇的我
No, sir. I work for the parish,
我要打理好几处呢
cover several properties.
I-23
I-23?
I-23收到  请指示
I-23. Go.
记录鉴定部门有回复了
I've got comeback on your R&I.
雷金纳德·勒杜  1960年11月13日出生
Reginald Ledoux -- DOB 11/13/60.
你知道当时还有谁
You know anybody who went here
来过这或者在这工作吗
or worked here back then?
没了  长官
Mm, no, sir.
我才来了几个月
I only been coming here the last few months.
教区刚把这里分给我
Parish added it to my work order.
感谢你抽出时间
Thank you for your time.
谁走路会这么慢啊
Who walks that fucking slow?
有消息了
What you got?
记录鉴定有回复了
R&I just came back.
雷金·勒杜8个月前逃离了假释
Reggie Ledoux skipped parole 8 months ago.
身上一堆案底  被控强奸
He's got a stat. Rape complaint,
后来被撤诉  但是93年再次被捕
charges dropped, but '93, he's busted
这次和一个毒品实验室有关
in connection to a narcotics lab
它们制造冰毒和迷幻药
used to make meth and LSD,
正是朵拉·兰和莉安身上查出的毒品
which Dora Lange and Rianne were full of.
继续
Right.
勒杜在阿沃伊斯蹲了两年
Ledoux did two years at Avoyelles,
猜猜他最后四个月的室友是谁
and guess who his cellmate was the last 4 months.
查理·兰
Charlie Lange.
这回我必须承认你说对了
I got to give you this one.
我开始相信
I started to believe you were going
你没那么疯了
a little off your nut.
你确实是个疯子  但是这件事上没疯
I mean, you're bonkers, just not on this.
好吧  那勒杜在哪儿
All right. Where was Ledoux?
我拿到了一份亲属和联系人名单
Getting a list of relatives, KAs.
自从他假释期脱逃后就没人见到过他
Been out of pocket since jumping parole.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
这下就能说通了
This makes sense.
情况不错  宝贝儿
Looks good, baby.
我们现在正赶去
All right. We are on our way.
阿沃伊斯
To Avoyelles.
太棒了  马丁  我们走
Fuck, yeah, Martin. Let's go.
我把情况通报给联邦执法部
I'm calling the interstate APB
再发一份通缉令
and the U.S. Marshals on this.
I-23呼叫总部
I-23 to dispatch.
收到  I-23
Come in, I-23.
我能说什么呢
What can I say?
我原来以为你就是喜欢
I thought for a minute, you just liked looking
看死人的照片
at pictures of dead people.
我要发布一份通缉令  对象是雷金纳德·勒杜
I need an all-state APB on one Reginald Ledoux.
记录鉴定部门查到了线索
R&I came back with info.
请通告联邦执法部和高速巡警
All U.S. Marshals and Highway Patrol,
一经发现  立即扣押  完毕
be advised, detain on sight, over.
收到  警探
Roger that, detective.
消息已经发出去了
We've got that sent now.
最终
And finally,
我们找到了雷金纳德·勒杜
we arrive at Reginald Ledoux.
快点  伙计们
Come on, man.
你们想问什么就问吧
You want to ask me, ask, goddamn it.
你遇到过枪战吗
You ever been in a gunfight?
没有
No.
那你们又他妈怎么理解
Well, then how the fuck you gonna know
我说得事情
what I'm talking about?
那地方  我从来
Man, that place-- I never--
那天  那地方让我想起我爸经常提到的越南
That day, it reminded me of my pop talking about 'Nam
和丛林战
and the jungle thing.
我现在跟你们说当时发生了什么
Look. Me talking about what happened back then,
对你们也没什么帮助
that ain't gonna do you any good now.
这个
This--
这个才是我要说的
This is what I'm talking about.
我每次说到时间
This is what I mean
死亡  和无效尝试时
when I'm talking about time and death
我指的就是这个
and futility.
工作时会有更多的想法
There are broader ideas at work,
这些想法来自于  人类整体作为一个社会
mainly what is owed between us as a society
所持有的相同的错觉
for our mutual illusions.
盯着尸体看上十四个小时
14 straight hours of staring at DBs,
你就会想到这些事情
these are the things you think of.
你做过吗
You ever done that?
你注视着他们的眼睛  即使只是照片
You look in their eyes, even in a picture.
他们是死是活都无关紧要
Doesn't matter if they're dead or alive.
你都能读出你要的信息  知道你会看出什么吗
You can still read them, and you know what you see?
你会看出他们也乐意你这么做
They welcomed it,
也许一开始不会
mm-hmm, not at first,
但是到了最后一刻总会如此
but right there in the last instant.
很明显这是一种解脱  因为他们原先会害怕
It's an unmistakable relief, see, because they were afraid
然后他们会第一次发现
and now they saw for the very first time
放手是如此简单
how easy it was to just let go,
而在那最后一刻  他们会看到
and they saw -- in that last nanosecond,
他们会看清自己
they saw what they were,
你  你自己  和这一系列闹剧
that you, yourself, this whole big drama,
不过是粗劣的假设和愚蠢的愿望
it was never anything but a jerry-rig
而现在你可以放手了
of presumption and dumb will and you could just let go
反正已经无需再坚持
finally now that you didn't have to hold on so tight...
也不用去管你的生活
to realize that all your life--
你的爱恨与纠葛
you know, all your love, all your hate,
你的回忆与苦痛  都是一体
all your memory, all your pain-- it was all the same thing.
都是同一个梦  一个你在密室中
It was all the same dream, a dream that you had
才会做的梦
inside a locked room,
一个关于如何做人的梦
a dream about being a person...
和许多其他的梦一样
and like a lot of dreams...
梦的最后  都有一头怪物
there's a monster at the end of it.